americanupbeat.com 2018-08-20

# Privacy Policy - American Upbeat

### **Privacy Policy**

#### **PLEASE REVIEW THE PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY**

Protecting your private information is our priority. We are committed to maintaining robust privacy protections for our users. The following describes how AmericanUpbeat (“AmericanUpbeat”, “we”, “us”) uses and disseminates information you provide us through www.AmericanUpbeat.com and its sub-domains and affiliated sites, as well as AmericanUpbeat pages and accounts on Facebook® (the “Sites). If you have questions about this Privacy Policy (“Policy”) please contact us at the information below. Please also review our full Terms and Conditions, which also govern your use of the Sites.

#### **Information** **W** **e** **Collect From You**

Unless expressly noted otherwise, we do not collect personally-identifiable information from users of our Sites. There is information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by us, such as your IP address, browser type, domain name, access time and referring website addresses. We use this information in improving and analyzing the Sites and for troubleshooting purposes. We also utilize this information to monitor and improve services and to ensure that your use of the Sites is in compliance with our Terms and Conditions.

#### **International Privacy Laws and Your Rights Under The GDPR**

If you are visiting the Sites from outside the United States, please be aware that you are sending information to the United States where our servers are located. Information you submit may then be transferred within the United States or back out of the United States to other countries outside of your country of residence, depending on the type of information and how it is stored by us. These countries (including the United States) may not necessarily have data protection laws as comprehensive protective as your country of residence; however, our collection, storage, and use of your data will at all times continue to be governed by this Policy. If you are a member of the European Union (EU), you have special rights under the GDPR. Those include: You have the right to object to the processing of your data and the right to portability of your data. All complaints must be sent to policy@americanupbeat.com. You also have the right to erasure, rectification, access, or to seek restrictions to the processing of your personal data in our system. To the extent you provide consent to our processing of your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Any withdrawal of consent does not apply to data collected lawfully prior to such consent. You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority containing jurisdiction over GDPR related issues.

#### **Updating Your Personally Identifiable Information**

We believe you should have the ability to access and edit the personal information that you have provided to us. You may change any of your personal information by contacting us here:

Email: [policy@americanupbeat.com](mailto:policy@americanupbeat.com)

#### **Use Of Your Personal Information**

If you do provide us with your personal information, we will not willingly share your information with companies outside our organization except as described in the Policy. We may disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe our services to potential advertisers, other third parties, our affiliate companies, and for other lawful purposes. You may receive communications from us related to our Sites. You will at all times be able to opt out from receiving these communications by specifically choosing to do so by contacting us here:

Email: [policy@americanupbeat.com](mailto:policy@americanupbeat.com)

The information we gather from you may be used in several ways, now or in the future, to gain a better understanding of our users and their usage pattern as a whole, for site administration and troubleshooting, to process transactions, contest entries and other matters you initiate, to identify preferences in content and advertising, to target editorial, advertising or other content (such as promotions, special offers or other content).

We do not give away, sell, rent or lease users’ personally identifiable information to any merchant, advertiser or web publisher. Non-personally identifiable user information (such as usage pattern, browser type and your computer) may be shared with third party businesses or advertisers with which we have a business or contractual relationship.

We reserve the right to disclose personal information when needed to comply with the law or a legal process, cooperate with investigations of purported unlawful activities, to identify persons violating the law, in connection with the sale of part or all of AmericanUpbeat’s or its affiliates assets, or to enforce our Terms and Conditions.

Please keep in mind that if you disclose personally identifiable information in a public manner through the Sites, this information may be collected and used by others accessing those portions of the Sites. We do not monitor information you disclose on the Sites nor do we accept any liability associated with your voluntary disclosure of the same. You are responsible for reviewing the privacy statements and policies of other websites you choose to link to or from the Sites, so that you may understand how those sites collect, use and store your information. We are not responsible for the privacy statements, policies or content of other websites. Websites containing co-branding (referencing our name and a third party’s name) contain content delivered by the third party and not us.

#### **Cookies**

A cookie is a data text file sent from a website to your browser. It may be stored within your system. The cookie identifies the user and allows access to articles. To the extent we use cookies, we can only access information from a cookie sent by one of the Sites, not other websites. We may use cookies to personalize your visit to our Sites. By tracking usage, we can best determine the needs of our customers and advertisers.

Although most browsers automatically accept cookies, you can choose whether or not to accept cookies via your browser’s settings (often found in your browser’s Tools or Preferences menu). You may also delete cookies from your device at any time. However, please be aware that if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to fully experience some of our Sites’ features.

Further information about managing cookies can be found in your browser’s help file or through sites such as [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

#### **Google Analytics**

AmericanUpbeat uses Google Analytics. More information about how Google Analytics is used by AmericanUpbeat can be found here:

<http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>

To provide our users with more choice on how their data is collected by Google Analytics, Google have developed the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. The add-on communicates with the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js) to indicate that information about the website visit should not be sent to Google Analytics. The Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on does not prevent information from being sent to the website itself or to other web analytics services.

#### **Social Media Widgets and Applications**

AmericanUpbeat Sites may include functionality to enable sharing via third party social media applications, such as the Facebook Like and Share buttons. These social media applications may collect and use information regarding your use of AmericanUpbeat Sites. Any personal information that you provide via such social media applications may be collected and used by other members of that social media application and such interactions are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide the application. We do not have control over, or responsibility for, those companies or their use of your information. The purpose of social media features is to facilitate the sharing of knowledge and content. Any personal information that you provide on any AmericanUpbeat social media feature may be shared with other users of that social media feature over whom we may have limited or no control.

#### **Children**

Our Sites are not intended for individuals under the age of 18. We do not collect or maintain information from anyone known to be under the age of 18, and no part of the Sites is designed to attract anyone under the age of 18. If you are under 18, you may only use the Sites under the supervision of a parent or guardian. If we discover or are otherwise notified that we have received any such information from a child in violation of this Policy, we will delete that information.

#### **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

AmericanUpbeat will occasionally update this Policy to reflect our current privacy practices. AmericanUpbeat encourages you to periodically review our Policy to be informed of how AmericanUpbeat is protecting your private information.

#### **Contact Us**

AmericanUpbeat welcomes your questions or comments regarding the Policy at policy@americanupbeat.com.

_________________

Email Address: policy@americanupbeat.com

_________________

Effective as of May 01, 2018
